本片根据真实故事改编
宾州南部斯坦顿
天气预报: 阳光灿烂
The forecast: plenty of sunshine today
气温正常
with seasonal temperatures,
下午高温会到达华氏82度
we should reach our normal high over this afternoon.
晚上爽朗
Clear skies tonight.
明天天气转为阴湿
Increasing cloudiness tomorrow, sticky and humid.
嘿 亲我一下 你要乖乖的
Hey. hey! Come give me a kiss. Be good.
- 再见 - 再见!
- Bye. - Bye!
好好上课!
Have fun!
克里夫 是1955年
Cleve, it's 1 955.
俱乐部里的动画片真是刻板
Please re- enter the clubhouse in a more stereotypically animated fashion.
宾州南部布鲁斯特
法兰克巴恩在哪里?
Hey. man. you know where I could find Frank Barnes?
- 你说什么? - 法兰克巴恩
- Sir? - Frank Barnes.
祝好运
Good luck.
谢谢
Thanks.
不好意思 我要找法兰克巴恩
Excuse me. I'm looking for Frank Barnes.
我就是
You found him.
我是威尔考森
I'm Will Colson.
我们今天要一起在1206列车工作
We're working together today on train 1 206.
- 1206 - 没错
- 1 206. - That's the one.
- 你的简历吗? - 没错 看一下吗?
- That's the profile? - Yeah. Want to take a look?
你好吗?
How you doing?
有什么问题吗?
Is there a problem?
没问题
No problem.
我只是不喜欢在幼稚园工作
I just don't like working in a damn day- care center.
我也不喜欢在养老院工作...
Yeah. well. I don't like working at a retirement home. so...
够了
All right. I'll tell you what.
我先喝完咖啡 然后车上见
I'm gonna finish my coffee. I'll meet you on the wagon.
好
Sounds good.
- 1206列车 - 没错
- 1 206. - Yeah. That's the one.
你们知道他是工会的人吧?
You know that punk's union. right?
他们让他当了谈判代表
Heard they just made him a shop steward at the UTU.
第一年加入?
First year?
你们知道他是怎么被录取的? 他姓考森
You know how he got hired? His name's Colson.
两个叔叔都是高层的人
His two uncles are running things over at Thornwood
兄弟是焊接工主管
and his brother's lead welder at Deacon.
整个家族都是斯坦顿来的
The whole family's from Stanton.
就是这样
That figures.
公司整天都在解雇员工
Here. they're shit- canning guys every day.
但只要姓的对 不管资历如何
but you got the right last name and a rookie's pay grade.
就会有工作
you got a job.
宾州北部富勒调度场
这些家伙在干嘛?
What the hell are these guys?
杜伊 葛利
Dewey. Gilleece.
抱歉打断你们
Sorry to break up charm school,
那个柴油车头在D16号轨道干嘛?
but what the hell is that beast still doing on D- 1 6?
我不是跟你们说要清空吗?
I told you I need that track clear.
别紧张 我们正要移开
Relax. buddy. We were just about to move it.
少来这一套
Like hell you are.
有150个学生校外教学要用到D16轨道
I've got 1 50 school students coming in on some field trip on D- 1 6.
我需要轨道清空
I need that track cleared.
D10是空的 把车头移过去
D- 1 0's clear. You can set it there.
好了 大家安静 大家安静
All right. All right. settle down. Settle down.
宾州北部惠岭
欢迎参加铁路安全讲习
Welcome to the Railroad Safety Campaign.
这是政府办的活动
We're a not- for- profit program
目的是让你们了解铁路安全的重要
designed to educate young people like yourselves about railway safety.
大家安静
Hey. settle down.
举手代表
Show of hands.
谁有坐过火车?
Who's ridden a train before?
我! 我!
Me! Me!
好 大家上车!
All right! All aboard!
今天要做什么?
So what's our day?
我们只要调度火车头
They got us going on light power.
过了斯坦顿接25节车厢
We're supposed to pick up 25 cars just past Stanton
然后通过威金斯
then it's pretty much a straight shot through Wilkins.
有慢车吗?
Any slow orders?
- 没有 - 你确定?
- No. - You sure?
有就会用红色标示
They'd be highlighted in red.
没有慢车
No. No slow orders.
好
All right.
杜伊 为什么这么久?
Dewey, what the hell is taking you so long?
39节车厢
It's a 39- car consist. Bunny.
有半哩长耶
The thing's half a mile long. for Christ's sake.
葛利 说话
Gilleece. channel up.
葛利 收到
Go for Gilleece.
这太扯了
You believe this shit?
等一下 空气管线没接好
Hey. hold up. You forgot to tie the air in from the point.
那又怎样?
Yeah. so?
你没有刹车
So. you don't have any air brakes.
我不要听邦尼碎念
You can tie the hoses once we got her parked
车停好再弄
and Bunny's quit his bitching.
好
Okay.
我只有一个规矩
I only got one rule.
唯一一个规矩
One rule only.
事情要做对
You gonna do something. you do it right.
不清楚就问 明白吗?
You don't know how to do it. ask me. all right?
宾州南部布鲁斯特调度场
如果你需要什么 就问我
Likewise. if you need anything from me. you better speak up
因为你是列车长
'cause you're the conductor.
我们一上路 车就是你的
Once we get our freight. it's your train.
我只是驾驶
I'm just the guy driving it.
你训练结束多久?
How long you been out of training?
四个月
About four months.
四个月? 哇
Four months? Wow. Yeah.
有够菜的
Full- on yellow vest rookie.
你在铁道工作多久了?
How long you been railroading?
28年 从81年11月13日起
Twenty- eight years. November 1 3. 1 981. 28 years.
你之前做什么的?
What did you do before that?
就一堆工作换来换去
Oh. I don't know. A bunch of different jobs.
- 没做过铁道? - 没有
- Yeah? No railroading? - No.
就想做不一样的
Just looking to do something different.
不一样?
Something different?
你是说更好吗?
What do you mean. something better?
不...
No. Just...
不一样 就换个不一样的
Different. Just different.
杜伊 快一点
Hey. Dewey. want to pick it up a little bit. jagoff?
我还想要吃完午餐
I want to have lunch at some point.
- 什么事 - 嘿
- Yeah. - Hey.
你的律师刚打来 好消息
Your lawyer just called. You got a break.
听证会改到今天早上
The hearing's been moved up to this morning.
看来你有机会回家了
Looks like you'll be going home.
那太好了 但是...
Well. that's great. but...
你有告诉他我在工作吗?
Did you tell him I was working?
我来不了
I can't come in.
我说了 他说没问题
Yeah. yeah. yeah. He said no problem. man.
- 状况看来不错 - 好的
- It's looking good. - All right.
等会帮我再打给他 再告诉我状况
Call him in an hour or two. see where it's at.
- 好 - 再打给我
- I will. - And then give me a call.
我们有没有要出发?
We ready to pull out or what?
马上来
Coming.
好
All right.
火车可不等人的
Train's leaving.
油料表读数多少?
What's our fuel gauge reading?
油料表读数2900
Fuel gauge. 2.900.
2900!
2.900!
角旋塞关闭 手刹车放开
Angle- cock's closed. hand brake's knocked off.
很好 很好
Good. good. good.
路线资料 内部通知都准备好
Got all the updated division notices and bulletin orders.
POS信息收到
The POS releases are in.
发车资料记录也填妥 我们可以出发了
Filled out our time slips. We're good to go.
很好 很好
Good. All right.
29节 还剩10节 状况不错
You're at 29 cars. You got 1 0 to go. You're good.
杜伊 29节加10节是...
Dewey, you got 29. Ten more makes...
你要把PB9移到D10 ?
You taking PB- 9 over to D- 1 0?
杜伊
Dewey.
等一下
Hold your horses.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
轨道切换不对 我会往D16去
Damn trailing point switch. The track's aligned for D- 1 6.
要多久才能停下来?
What's your stopping distance?
至少要20节车厢长 该死!
At least 20 cars to a stop. Damn it!
那我们多花点时间先后退
Okay. so we back it up and lose a little time.
我下去改
I'm hopping out.
不要离开驾驶厢!
Do not get out of that cab. man!
不用担心 我会设定独立刹车
Don't worry. I'll set the independent.
杜伊 杜伊!
Dewey! Dewey!
无人驾驶
快回去
Come on, get back on.
杜伊 快点回去!
Dewey! You better get back on!
我过去了
I'm on it. I'm on it.
前进
该死!
Shit!
你最好快上车
You better get back on. dickhead.
嘿!
Hey!
该死!
Shit!
做得好!
Nice job. Dewey!
该死!
God damn it!
现在我们怎么办?
So now what the hell do we do?
宾州南部麦尔斯堡调度站
"妮可生日"
该死
Shoot.
你麻烦大了
Ooh. you're in trouble.
别乱说 找你姊接电话
Just don't talk about it. Just put your sister on the phone. sweetheart.
爸找你
Dad.
她不想跟你说话
She doesn't want to talk to you.
就跟她说我没忘 我只是...
Listen. Just tell her I was... I didn't forget. I was just...
我会晚点到
I was running late.
她晚上有约会
She's got a date tonight.
跟谁?
With who?
叫她接电话就对了
Just put your sister on the phone.
等一下 我叫她接
Wait. Here she is.
妮琪?
Nic?
Nicky?
喂?
Hello?
听着...
Listen. just...
宝贝 我没...
Baby, look, I didn't forget. I was...
车头掉转好了 有问题吗?
Frank. the stop blocks are up. Is there a problem?
没问题 只是你方向弄反了
No. there's no problem. except you got it backwards.
转盘机房该在我这边 你该在另外一头
Turntable house goes on my end. You're on the ballast.
在我这边
On my end.
除此之外 没问题
Other than that, no problem. No problem at all.
我说过
Like I told you.
如果不清楚 就问我
if you don't know something. just ask. That's all.
了解
I got it.
最好是
I hope so.
随便你
Whatever.
你说什么?
Excuse me?
这套"让新人证明自己"的狗屁
This shit. This "Let's make the new guy prove himself" bullshit.
我早就听过 我可不吃这一套
I gotta tell you. I've heard it before and it gets old real fast.
在养老院我们就是这样做
Well. that's how it is at the retirement home.
公司想把我们这些老鸟赶走
Company wants to get rid of us old heads.
把工作给你们这些新人 年轻小伙子
They give all the jobs to you new guys. you yellow vests.
我没有要抢任何人的工作
I'm not trying to take anything from anybody.
不管你怎么说
As reassuring as that is.
大部分人的看法就是这样
a lot of guys don't see it that way.
我到了 马上就会进去
I'm here. I'm walking in right now.
带了好几盒甜甜圈给孩子们吃
I got a car full of donuts for those kids.
- 滑行车? 哪一台? - 康妮?
- A coaster? What train? - Connie?
这是怎么发生的?
How the hell did this happen?
车就这样跑掉了
It just got away from me.
车就这样跑掉了?
It got away from you?
那是火车 不是宠物
It's a train. Dewey. not a chipmunk.
我离开驾驶厢去改轨道开关
I had to leave the cab to throw a switch.
- 你离开驾驶厢? - 对
- You left the cab? - Yeah.
还不只这样
And it gets worse.
空气刹车没有接上 还没有接上
The air brakes weren't tied on. They aren't tied on. still.
有一辆无人列车逆向在轨道前进
We've got an unmanned train rolling into opposing traffic
还没有刹车?
with no air brakes. is that what you're telling me?
我有设定独立刹车 它迟早会停
I set the independent brakes. That'll for sure stop it.
速度有多快?
How fast is it going?
一小时不超过十哩
No more than 1 0 miles per.
开维修车去追
Okay. Jump on the hi- rail and go after it.
立刻去!
Now!
好 你是老大
Okay. ballbuster.
联络旅游车!
Call the field trip!
不管他们到了哪里
I don't care where they are on the main line.
请他们 马上进侧线
they need to get into the nearest siding.
旅游车 这是富勒调度场 请回答
RS Campaign. RS Campaign. This is Fuller Yard. Do you copy?
控制中心 收到 有何指示
RSC answering dispatch. How can I help you? Over.
旅游车 这是富勒调度场
RS Campaign. this is Fuller Yard.
轨道上发现未核准的活动
We've got unauthorized activity on your track.
请改道到最近的波特维尔侧线
We're gonna need you to divert to a siding at Portville.
控制中心 请重复
Dispatch. please repeat.
请重复
Please repeat. Over.
什么时候可以坐火车?
What time is train time?
任何时候!
Anytime!
改道到最近的波特维尔侧线 有没有收到?
Divert to a siding in Portville. Do you copy?
收到 我会改道到波特维尔侧线
I copy. I'll divert into the siding at Portville. Over.
给我777号列车的载货资料
Get me 777's cargo information.
我需要通报总公司
I have to call corporate and report this.
杜伊说他有设定独立刹车
Now. Dewey said he applied the independent.
阻力应该会在几哩后让列车停下
so friction should stop the damn thing after a few miles.
我们要通知所有主线北行的列车
Still. we need to alert every northbound train on the mainline.
20哩范围内的列车优先
First 20 miles of track take priority.
不管你说的
I don't care if you're talking about
是在维修轨道整修火车
a spot weld on a Class 3 rip track
或是在阿富汗的行动 精准度最重要
or ground operations in Afghanistan. it's all about precision.
- 没错 - 谢谢
- Right. - Thank you.
- 不好意思 - 没问题
- Excuse me. - Sure.
喂
Hello.
奈德 你在哪里?
Ned. where are you?
康妮 我快到公司了
Oh. Connie. I'm just driving in now.
我要走了
I got to go.
你离五号工作站多远?
How far are you from milepost 5?
大约六分钟 这要看交通状况
Roughly six minutes. traffic contingent.
好极了 我需要你马上过去
Great. I need you to haul ass over there
切换轨道 我们有滑行车状况
and throw the siding switch. We got a coaster.
滑行车? 真的吗?
A coaster? Really?
它应该15分钟后会经过五号站
Yeah. It should roll past MP 5 in about 1 5 minutes.
你有足够的时间切换轨道
That should give you enough time to throw the switch.
让它离开主线进入侧线
get it off the mainline and onto that siding.
你要我爬上车停下它?
You want me to climb onboard and stop it?
不用 有两个工作人员过去了 你只要切换轨道就好
What? No. Two hostlers are on the way. Just throw the switch. Ned.
收到
Roger that.
他永远都迟到
You can always count on him to be late.
我晚点回来
I'll see you later.
再见!
See you!
Yeah, I can get you where you need to go
'Cause I'm a country boy
我们到了平交道该怎么办?
What do we do when we get to a railroad crossing?
停、看、听!
Stop. Iook and listen!
我听不到!
I can't hear you!
停、看、听!
Stop. Iook and listen!
宾州南部斯坦顿弯道
限速15哩
你是斯坦顿人?
You from Stanton?
在这里出生长大
Born and raised. Yeah?
我们家族都是斯坦顿人
My whole family's from Stanton.
结婚了?
Married?
对
Yeah.
算吧 说来话长
Well. sort of. It's a long story.
我们有大把时间
We got a long day.
你呢? 结婚了?
How about you? You married?
说来话短 一次
Short story. Once.
有两个宝贝女儿 18岁跟19岁
Got two beautiful daughters. though. 1 8. 1 9.
她们都是服务生 打工念大学
They are both waitressing. trying to work their way through college.
- 是吗? - 是的
- Oh. yeah? - Yeah.
- 在哪里打工? - 辣妹参厅
- Where at? - Hooters.
辣妹参厅? 你知道吗? 好
Hooters. You know? All right.
别怀疑 就是辣妹参厅 把脸上那个奇怪笑容收起来
That's right. Hooters. Wipe that grin off your face.
- 我很喜欢那个地方 - 当然
- I'm a fan. - Yeah.
你脸都红了
You're blushing.
我习惯了
I'm used to it.
康妮 总公司在二线
Connie. Corporate on line 2.
我是富勒调度场的康妮胡波
This is Connie Hooper at Fuller Yard.
我会等
I'll hold.
听说你有滑行车 真的吗?
Did I hear right? You've got a coaster?
偶发事件 我们在处理了
Yeah. This sort of thing happens. We're on it.
停的下来吗?
Won't it trip a relay?
听着 我要直接跟盖文先生报告
Listen. I need to speak to Mr. Galvin directly.
我了解 可以请他回电吗?
I see. Can you have him call me. then?
不 我正要看货物清单
No. I'm about to review the cargo shipment myself.
你是谁?
Who the hell are you?
我来做铁路安全讲习
I'm here for the Railroad Safety Campaign.
史考特华纳 联邦铁路局第二区安全检查员
Scott Werner. FRA Region 2. Federal Safety Inspector.
我来替学童上课
I'm supposed to give a presentation to the children.
- 讲一些基本安全知识 - 嘿 邦尼!
- go over some basic stuff. That's great. - Hey. Bunny? Bunny!
帮我一下好吗?
Can you help me out here?
你看到那个人了吗?
Okay. see this guy right there?
他会带你去坐下
He's gonna tell you where to sit.
轨道地理学 等等...
Track geometry. alignment...
谢谢 我带了测量仪来...
Thank you so much. I brought some gauges...
小朋友会喜欢 太好了
The kids are gonna love that. It's great.
他妈的 这东西到底在哪里?
God damn it. Where the hell is this thing?
液态酚 危险物质
邦尼 我要知道7到10车装什么
Bunny? I need to know exactly what's in cars 7 to 1 0.
请帮我联络寄货人
Get a hold of the shipper. please.
开什么玩笑?
Are you kidding me?
火车呢?
Where's the train?
你说火车在哪里?
Where does it look like the goddamn train is?
我不知道 你在这里干什么?
It's not here! What are you doing out here?
我有可能把火车藏在口袋里吗?
Do I look like I got a train hidden in my back pocket?
邦尼 帮我接给康妮 我是奈德
Bunny. get me Connie. It's Ned.
到后面去 SB
Get behind us. jackass.
- 你太慢到了 - 少来这一套
- Did you get here too late? - Don't give me that shit.
你们两个白痴老把事情搞砸
You two numbnuts are always screwing up.
你调换轨道了吗?
You switched the track that was supposed to get the train on the right track.
康妮 我是奈德
Connie. Yeah. it's Ned.
你把开关弄好没?
Did you throw that switch yet?
6分钟前就弄好了 但没看到火车
Yeah. six minutes ago. but your train. it's not here.
我以为车速比你想的慢
I thought it might be going a little slower than you guessed,
但你派来的两个白痴刚出现
but these two numbnuts that you sent.
他们也没看到
they just showed up and they ain't seen it. either.
你是说火车已经过去了?
Are you saying our train's already passed?
我想是这样
Yes. ma'am. That'd be my guess.
它不是滑行车 火车有动力
It's not a coaster. That train's under power.
我也是这么认为
That'd be my guess. too.
- 叫杜伊接电话 - 好的
- Put Dewey on the phone. - Sure.
她要跟你说话 浑蛋
She wants to talk to you. asshole.
好的
Yeah.
我要你用力地想
I need you to rally every cell in that brain of yours.
你设定独立刹车的时候
When you applied the independent.
油门在前进的状态吗?
was the throttle in the forward position?
没错 我要让它移动!
Yeah. I had to get it moving!
油门放在什么位置?
In what position was the throttle set?
该死 在什么位置?
Damn it. Dewey. what position?
油门在第八格全速前进
Connie. the throttle was in notch 8. full power.
它拖了39节车!
Okay? It was 39 cars!
好
Okay.
往南跟上去
Take the southbound track. Catch up.
看你们能不能爬上去
See if it's still going slow enough for one of you to climb on.
你要等到13号哩程标轨道才会分开
You have got until milepost 1 3 before the track splits.
让我跟奈德说话
Let me talk to Ned again.
做得好 浑蛋!
Nice job. asshole!
奈德 我要你回到车上跟着主线 明白吗?
Ned. I want you to get back in your car and follow the mainline. Okay?
我要你盯住列车
I want a set of eyes on that train.
没问题 了解
You got them. Roger that.
我听不到!
I can't hear you!
铁路安全非常重要!
Railroad Safety Campaign!
宾州南部锌工厂
没问题
You're good.
还有50尺
Keep it coming. 50.
20尺
20 feet.
减速
Slow down.
搞定了
All right. you're good.
杰西 怎么了?
Yeah. What's going on?
可以讲话吗?
You got a minute?
他不是说状况很好?
I thought he said it was looking good.
他本来这么想
That's what he thought.
但是遇上的法官非常难搞
Turns out the judge they assigned was a real hard- ass.
别开玩笑了
You gotta be kidding me.
保护令又被延长了30天
Look. the restraining order is being continued for another 30 days.
30天? 我该怎么办?
Thirty days? What am I supposed to do for 30 days?
不能接近孩子?
Stay away from my kid?
还会有一个听证会
And then there's another hearing after that. I guess.
威尔 怎么这么慢?
What's taking you so long. Will?
你打电话给那个律师
You call that lawyer. you can tell him
叫他去死 我得做事了
he can stick it up his ass. I got to go.
威尔 拿起无线电
Will, pick up the radio.
威尔 拿起无线电 完毕
Will. pick up the radio. Over.
你在吗?
Are you there?
在
Yeah.
别再讲电话了 放开手刹车
Yeah. Get off the phone. knock off the hand brakes.
快上来 该走了 还有活要干
get up here. It's time to go. We got work to do.
收到
Copy.
确定有动力
No. it's definitely under power.
但车速还不确定
We're not sure of the exact speed yet.
这些车不是都有紧急刹车装置?
I thought all these trains had some sort of dead- man brake.
但要靠人力启动
There's a wand the engineer has to hit periodically
不然还能靠空气刹车
or the air brakes are automatically applied.
不幸的是 空气刹车没有连接
Unfortunately. this train's air brakes were disconnected.
我很乐意解释火车头基本操作
Sir, I would gladly explain the particulars of locomotive operation to you
如果有足够的时间 但现在我需要您的协助
if we had time. but right now I really need your assistance
派遣警员到所有主线上的平交道
posting officers at all the mainline crossings.
一个问题
One question.
你们打算如何让车停下来?
How do you all plan to stop it?
我们还在想办法
We're working on it.
快快 前面又要分轨了!
Go. go. go! The split's coming up!
你确定上的去?
Are you sure you can do this?
开到驾驶厢旁就对了
Just get alongside of the cab.
开到驾驶厢旁边!
Get up alongside of it!
我在努力了!
I'm trying!
快点!
Go. go. go!
记住 我们没剩多少轨道了!
Remember. we don't have a lot of track!
可以了 快上去!
You got it. go. go!
杜伊!
Dewey!
太快了 慢一点!
It's too fast! Back it up!
杜伊 慢一点!
Come on. Dewey! Go back!
葛利 快上去!
Jump. Gilleece! Do it!
快回车里 小心!
Get in! Watch out!
这下我们该怎么办?
So now what the hell do we do?
我们该挂多少节车厢?
How many cars are we supposed to cut in?
20节 怎么了?
Twenty. Why?
20节 好
Twenty cars. okay.
有看到前面的开关标志吗?
See the switch stand up ahead of us?
开关标志?
The switch stand. yeah? Uh- huh.
看后视镜 看到后面那个了吗?
Take a look in the rear view mirror. You see the one behind us?
最后面那边 看到了吗?
Way back there. You see it? Uh- huh.
两个标志间刚好是21节的距离
There's exactly 21 cars between the two stands.
别问我怎么知道的
Don't ask me how I know.
那么为什么
So why is it that
还有4节半的车厢在距离外?
there's still more than four and a half cars that are yet to clear?
因为我...
Because I...
你说什么?
Excuse me?
- 因为我... - 因为什么?
- Because I cut... - Because what?
因为我挂了太多车厢
I cut in too many cars.
挂了太多车厢?
Cut in too many cars. huh?
如果不是你一直找我麻烦
Maybe if you weren't on my ass the whole time.
我就能好好思考做好工作
I might be able to think straight and do my job.
你什么意思 "也许 假如我..."
What do you mean. "Maybe. if I..."
你把事情推到我身上?
You been on my ass this whole trip! You're blaming it on me?
我只是说 找一个工作!
I'm just saying. pick a goddamn job!
我有工作了! 二选一!
I got my job! You pick one!
弄油门或者是插销! 二选一!
I pull the throttle. you pull the pin! It's one or the other!
你去弄插销 你多了五个插销
You're five pins too many.
弄好插销 你说的对
Pull the pins. You're right. pull the pins.
我有通过训练!
I've had my training! All right?
但这是实际上阵 不是训练
Yeah. but we're out here in the real world. This ain't training.
训练不合格 顶多被当掉 这里玩真的 没搞好你就没命
In training. they just give you an F. Out here. you get killed.
- 我错了 好吗? - 你的确错了
- I screwed up. okay? - Yes. you did.
停车 后退 我把空车拿掉
Stop and roll back and I'll cut the empties.
后退?
Roll back?
天啊
Oh. Lord.
我们在主线上不能停车
We can't stop out here on the main.
已经离开一哩了
We're more than a mile out on the main.
离下一站还有一哩多
more than a mile to the next stop.
这样的长度距离不能后退
You don't take a consist this size that distance in reverse.
好 那我们到一个侧线再倒转
Fine. Then we'll make the turn at the next siding.
下一个侧线还有十哩远
The next siding's not for 1 0 miles.
那样会迟到 我不想迟到
We do that. we're late. I don't run late.
记录下来就好
Just green- sheet it and we'll move on.
算了 做纪录就会害到我!
Come on. We green- sheet it and it's my ass! Cut me some slack.
什么意思 害到你? 你姓考森耶
What do you mean. it's your ass? You're a Colson.
那是什么意思?
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
意思是 你叔叔会帮你
That means you can call your uncle and they'll take care of it.
你是因为这样找我麻烦吗?
Is that what this is about?
不是 是因为多了5节车厢
No. it's about the five cars too many.
那我们就停车 后退 放掉多的车厢!
We're gonna stop. roll back and cut those empties!
这是你的车头 但列车是我的
This may be your engine. but it's my goddamn train.
- 这是你的列车没错 - 我才是列车长!
- Yes. it is. - I'm the goddamn conductor!
- 没错 - 呼叫1206列车
- That's true. - 1206, check in.
我要打你的小报告
I'll write you up and green- sheet your ass.
- 满意了? - 这样如何?
- Will you? - How about that?
1206列车 请回报位置 结束
1206, this is dispatch. What's your location? Over.
- 什么东西这么好笑 - 没事
- Something's funny? - No.
那你他妈的在笑什么? 那你在笑什么?
What the hell are you laughing at? What are you laughing at?
因为很有趣 你是个有趣的人
Because it's funny. You're a funny guy.
训练有素 但是好笑 这里是1206列车
Well- trained. but funny. Yeah. this is 1 206.
我们距离威尔森60哩
We're 60 miles from Wilkins.
距离富勒调度场40分钟
Forty minutes out of Fuller Yard.
宾州芬德雷中央调度中心
要求拒绝 请在下一个侧线离开
Negative. 1 206. Clear your train at the next siding
等候进一步指示
until further instructed. Over.
发生什么事?
What's up?
富勒有一辆无人列车正在北行中
There's an unmanned train out of Fuller, on the northbound track. Over.
跟我们同一轨道?
On our track?
滑行车?
A coaster?
我们没有进一步的消息
1 206. we don't have all the details yet.
请前往下一条侧线
Just proceed to the next siding and hold tight. Over.
下一条侧线还有10哩
Next siding's not for 1 0 miles.
了解 1206列车
Affirmative, 1206.
请尽速前往侧线
Just get in that siding and sit tight
等候指示
until we give you the all- clear. Over.
收到
Affirmative.
它正对我们而来
It's coming right at us.
有关宾州失控列车的进一步消息
More word on that runaway freight train in rural Pennsylvania.
列车编号AwvR 777
The train, A WVR777,
简称777
otherwise known as 777,
今早大约八点离开
Ieft Fuller Yard in northern PA
宾州北部的富勒调度场
sometime before 8: 00 a. m. this morning
车上无人控制
and no one was onboard.
最新当地消息
Live, local, late- breaking.
消息指出驾驶操控判断错误
The engineer, they say, made an error in controlling the train.
离开车厢前
Before leaving the locomotive,
他想启动独立刹车
he intended to apply the independent brakes.
等他发现错误时
And then by the time he realized his mistake,
列车速度已经太快无法再上车
the train was going too fast for him to climb back on.
据铁路管理局
We're being told now by a spokesperson
官方发言人表示
for the Public Utilities Commission
驾驶须承担所有责任
that this employee will be held accountable.
- 康妮? - 在
- Connie? - Yeah.
总公司来电 盖文在线上
Headquarters is on the phone. It's Galvin.
盖文先生 你好吗?
Mr. Galvin. how are you?
见鬼 这怎么可能发生?
God damn it. How could this happen?
宾州匹兹堡AwvR总部
这是人为错误与衰运的组合
It's an unfortunate combination of human error and bad luck.
运气?
Luck?
我当过调度场主管十年
I was a yardmaster for 1 0 years. Ms. Hooper.
运气在火车这一行不该存在
Luck has no business in a rail yard.
载货物有需要担心的吗?
What are we worried about in terms of cargo?
当然 油料需要担心
Well. obviously. the diesel fuel's a concern.
不 我在问货物
No, I said cargo.
7到10号
Okay. well. cars 7 through 1 0
16到19号列车 载运了化学原料液态酚
and 1 6 through 1 9 are carrying a chemical called molten phenol.
我们还在联系寄货人
We're still trying to connect with the shipper
了解它的用途
to determine exactly what that is.
那是用来生产黏剂的
It's used in the manufacture of glue.
能请你等一下吗?
Can you hold on one moment?
你懂液态酚的用途?
You know about molten phenol?
对
Yes.
盖文先生 现场有一位联邦铁路局的代表
Mr. Galvin. we have an FRA inspector here.
我可以用扩音吗?
May I put you on speaker?
我是第二区安全检查员史考特华纳 有什么可以帮忙?
Region 2 Federal Safety Inspector Scott Werner. How can I help?
快告诉我这玩意的用途
Just tell me what you know about molten phenol.
它是危险物质 毒性很强 非常易燃
Well. it's serious stuff. Very toxic. highly combustible.
太好了
Oh, that's terrific.
胡波 请联络州警
Hooper. get state police back on the line.
请他们派遣危险物质处理小组
Make sure they got a HazMat team briefed and ready.
派直升机跟紧777
And ask them to put a spotter chopper over 777.
你应该已经清除线上的列车?
I take it you've sided all rail traffic?
我们的都通知了 布鲁斯特那边会通知他们的列车
On our end, yes. Brewster's notifying its own.
长官
Sir.
我们该怎么处理?
how are we going to handle this?
列车会经过...
I mean. this train is en route to pass
人口密集的区域
through some highly populated areas.
我们两分钟后会开应变电话会议
We're having a strategy call in about two minutes.
我会准备好
All right. I'll be ready.
你不需要参加会议 胡波
You won't be on the call. Ms. Hooper.
- 什么? - 结论会通知你
- Excuse me? - You'll be advised.
你的当务之急是协调当地各单位
For now. coordinate with local authorities.
有超过一百个平交道需要控管
God knows we gotta have over 1 00 crossings that need to be secured.
共173个
One hundred and seventy- three.
平交道
Railroad crossings.
从这里到布鲁斯特分站
Between here and AWVR substation in Brewster.
听着 盖文先生
Listen. Mr. Galvin.
这列车的长度半哩
this train is half a mile long and is traveling at speed into population
载运八节有毒物质和五千加仑柴油
with eight freight cars of hazardous chemicals
加速前往人口密集区域
and 5, 000 gallons of diesel fuel.
这不是一般的列车
Sir, we're not just talking about a train here.
这是有如101大楼般的巨大飞弹
We're talking about a missile the size of the Chrysler Building.
你想讲什么?
So. what is your point. Ms. Hooper?
一旦它通过芬德雷
My point is after it crosses through Findlay.
会经过12哩的农地
there's about 1 2 miles of vacant farmland.
但之后一路到斯坦顿
but after that. it's nothing but town after town
全都是住宅区
all the way to Stanton.
我们手上的时间不多
We have a very limited window here.
你建议让它脱轨吗?
So. what are you suggesting we do. derail it?
是的
Yes. sir. I am.
趁我们还有机会的时候
While we still can.
我知道这样成本很大...
Mr. Galvin. I understand that's gonna cost the company a lot of money...
你知道多少吗?
Do you think?
我们不可能摧毁自己的列车
Ms. Hooper. we're not gonna intentionally destroy one of our own trains.
我们还有机会让列车停止
Not when we can still stop it.
这样可以避免...
We can avoid a lot of collateral...
我就当你刚才的建议是出于好心
I'm going to extend you my last ounce of good will
我会当做这段对话没有发生过
and pretend this conversation never happened.
他以为我怕我保不住饭碗
He thinks I'm worried about my job.
宾州北部芬德雷
请留在车内
Ma'am. please stay in your van.
- 来吧 - 请回到车上
- Come on. - Please get back into the van.
谁能告诉我发生什么事了?
Can you please tell us what's going on?
20哩内的所有平交道都封锁了
Every crossing's closed off for 20 miles.
夫人 为了你的安全 请回到车上
Ma'am. for your safety. please get back into your van.
我不回去
I'm not getting back in the vehicle.
我们要知道发生什么事
We need to know what's going on.
快点离开 列车来了
Guys. get out of there. There's a train coming.
快点!
Hurry!
快点 列车来了!
Hurry! It's coming!
该走了
Come on. We got to go.
让开 列车来了 快点!
Get out of there! Move it!
闪开!
Get out of the way!
1206呼叫中心
1 206 to dispatch. Over.
- 怎么了? - 怎么了?
- What's wrong? - What's wrong?
我们没办法进去那个侧线
We're not gonna fit in that siding. that's what's wrong.
1206呼叫中心
1 206 to dispatch. Over.
1206 你进侧线了没?
1 206. are you in the siding yet?
你的位置在哪里?
What's your location?
不 还没 我们进不去
No, we're not in the hole. We're not gonna make it, can't do it.
太多车厢了
Too much train.
我需要你更换轨道
I'm gonna need you to realign the switch
让我们前往下一个侧线
so we can proceed to the next siding.
1206 你需要马上离开主线
1 206. you have to get off the main. Over.
我了解 但你也要了解
I understand that. but you gotta understand this.
我们进不去
we're not going to fit.
1206 稍等
1206, stand by.
那个侧线有3千尺长
That siding's a good 3.000 feet. end to end.
时刻表上面
Check your timetable.
写的是4111尺
it's gonna tell you the siding is 4111 feet.
但那是两边号志间的总长
But that's signal to signal.
实际上大约是2500尺
In reality. it's more like 2.500 feet.
加上你多挂的五节车厢...
You add those five cars that you picked up...
可以进去
We can fit.
不 进不去
No, we won't fit.
1206呼叫中心
Dispatch. this is 1 206.
请告知最近的维修轨道位置
Can you tell me where the nearest rip track is?
6.2哩后有一个 你的速度多快?
1 206. there's one in 6.2 miles. How fast are you going?
551里
55 miles an hour.
开快一点
1 206. go faster. Over.
为什么 那台滑行车还在线上?
Why? Is that coaster still on the main?
1206 777不是滑行车 重复 不是滑行车
1206, 777 is not a coaster. I repeat, it is not a coaster. Over.
你是说它有动力?
You're telling me it's under power?
我们需要 马上进侧线
Get in the goddamn siding.
1206 稍等
1206, stand by.
1206 如果你要尝试 维修轨道是空的
1 206. if you're going for it. that rip track is confirmed vacant.
你决定 法兰克
It's your call, Frank.
如果你要继续下去 需要更改轨道
We need to throw the switch if you're staying on.
不继续 就拉刹车
We're not staying on! Pull the brake. Frank.
拉刹车进侧线就会出乱子
We pull the brake and side up. I crash.
我是老法师了
I know what the hell I'm doing.
- 胡扯 你会害死我们! - 嘿
- Bullshit! You're gonna get us killed. - Hey!
1206 我需要答案
1206, I need an answer. Over.
请切换轨道
Realign the switch.
完毕
Over.
当时里面没有人 就开走了
The train was just going with no one in it. Just took off.
我们说列车会经过这里
We were yelling on the radio earlier,
列车要来了
there's a runaway train coming through.
接下来会经过我们镇上
It could be coming to our town next
学校很接近铁路
and the high school's right next to those train tracks.
不久前
Just a few moments ago,
一辆失控列车高速经过...
a train came barreling down these tracks...
我们还在计算数字
We're still going over the numbers.
但如果777脱轨 就会造成极大灾难
but should 777 derail. we're looking at a major disaster.
任何一节危险车厢爆炸
If even one of those HazMat cars blew.
就可以夷平一个城镇
it could easily decimate an entire town.
列车上总共有八节危险车厢
That train is carrying eight of them.
能说说你看到的情况吗...
Can you please explain to our viewers what you witnessed...
环境和轨道赔偿加上列车损坏
Environmental liability. track damage. car and locomotive loss.
我们预估损失将超过1亿美金
We're looking at a projected cost easily over $1 00 million.
预估的股票跌幅呢?
And the resulting stock devaluation?
跌幅应该在三成到四成中间
Our projections indicate it could be in the 30 to 40% range.
我同意进行盖文的计划
I say we go with Mr. Galvin's option.
我已经联络好布鲁斯特分站
I've already prepped our substation in Brewster.
只需要命令就可以进行
They just need a go- ahead.
进行吧
You have it.
大家可以离开了
Okay. everybody out.
奥克曼留下
Hoffman. you stay here.
贝克 把富勒到斯坦顿间的轨道图给我
Baker. get me a track schematic. Fuller to Stanton. please.
我是欧文斯
This is Owens.
71哩 雷射枪显示时速70到71哩
7 1. 70. 7 1 on the gun.
红点的意思是?
So the red means?
777的路径
777 blew through a signal.
红点代表麻烦
Everything in red means trouble on the mainline.
红点也太多了吧
That's a lot of red.
康妮 盖文先生2线找
Connie, Mr. Galvin on line 2.
我是康妮胡波
This is Connie Hooper.
主线上的所有平交道都关闭了吗?
Have all the mainline crossings been closed?
是的 我请州警协助执行了
Yes, I've been coordinating with PSP.
我们有对应方式了吗?
Do we have a strategy in place?
已经在进行中
It's already underway.
宾州中部基丁峰
我后方的阵仗显示
By the activity level behind me,
他们正在尝试停下失控列车
it is evident that a plan to stop the runaway train is underway,
但目前铁路公司没有任何回应
but so far, no one at AWVR is commenting.
铁路公司员工雷恩史考特
We just witnessed A WVR employee Ryan Scott
登上其中一架救援直升机
boarding one of the rescue helicopters.
这位前陆战队员刚从阿富汗回国
He is a 22- year- old Marine vet who has just returned from Afghanistan.
- 这是怎么回事 - 我需要警察前导!
- What the hell is this? - I need a police escort now!
- 这上面说你是焊接工 - 焊接工主管
- It says here you're a welder. - Lead welder.
听着 老兄 我没有多少时间
Listen. buddy. I don't got a lot of time.
你们可以联络我主管 康妮胡波!
You can call my yardmaster. Connie Hooper!
- 康妮派你来的? - 没错
- Connie sent you? - That's what I said.
我需要你帮忙
I need your help.
中心呼叫1206
1206, this is dispatch.
我们计算过了 你们的长度超过两千尺 进不去
1 206. we ran the math. At over 2.000. you wouldn't have fit.
你的决定是对的
Good call. Over.
谢谢 我需要知道那辆列车的位置
Thank you. but I need to know where that oncoming train is.
它距离我们多远?
How far away is it?
1206 我们不确定
1206, we're not exactly sure.
你们不确定? 快点弄清楚啊!
You're not sure? Well. find out!
我在宾州中部的高空...
I'm high above central Pennsylvania. This train got away...
警方封锁了
Emergency responders want to halt all activity near the line
铁路1哩内的区域
and possibly evacuate all homes
并考虑疏散其中的居民
within a mile radius of the tracks.
列车载有几千加仑的易燃油料
There's thousands of gallons of fuel onboard, which is highly flammable.
我们等候进一步消息
But we're still awaiting word on that.
这就是盖文的计划?
This is Galvin's strategy?
看来他们试图要用另一辆车档在777前
Looks like they're putting a train in front of 777
让它减速
in an attempt to slow it down.
接着派出直升机载雷恩过去
Now, they are sending a chopper with Ryan Scott
铁路公司仍然拒绝回应
and the railroad company is still refusing to comment.
我们刚刚得知有26年经验的机师杰德
We've just learned that 26- year rail company veteran Judd Stewart
驾驶着
is at the controls of the engine
前方的火车
that is in front of the runaway train.
我是康妮胡波
This is Connie Hooper from Fuller Yard.
你的人要从直升机下来吗?
Is this your guy coming off the helicopter?
目前速度55哩
Still holding at 55.
减速到40 继续刹车
Get her down to 40 and keep braking.
该死!
Shit!
做的好 继续减速
That's it. Keep going. Keep slowing.
到了40哩我们就派人下去
Get her down to 40 and we'll set our boy down.
真是令人无法相信!
Unbelievable!
一定要成功!
Do this!
快点
Come on.
...太惊险了...
...incredibly dangerous...
杰德 加油!
Do this. Judd. come on!
低于40哩了 他上去了没?
I'm under 40. Is he on yet?
往下!
Now!
看来雷恩受伤了
Looks like Marine Ryan Scott has been injured.
没有成功 减速!
It's a no- go. Slow down!
继续减速 尽量让777离开主线
Just keep braking. Try to slow it. Try to get 777 off the main.
轨道已经切换
Switch has been thrown.
该死的东西 慢下来啊!
Slow down. God damn it!
不能切换到侧线 速度太快了
Don't side it yet! It's going too fast.
跳车!
Bail! Bail! Bail!
我的天啊!
Holy shit!
列车可能脱轨了
Maybe it derailed.
我无法形容刚刚有多夸张
Wow! I can't believe how crazy that was.
我的天啊 盖文 你这个混蛋!
Oh. my God! Galvin. you asshole!
富勒调度场 这是1206
Fuller Yard. Fuller Yard. This is 1 206.
我们正经过52号哩程标 在主线上往北前进
We're passing milepost 52. heading northbound on the Main 1.
1206 我在跟哪位说话
1 206. who am I speaking with?
法兰克巴恩 机师
Frank Barnes. the engineer.
我是康妮胡波 富勒主管
This is Connie Hooper. yardmaster at Fuller.
为什么你还在主线上?
Why are you still on the mainline?
我们本要进入侧线但没成功
We were directed to a siding that's a no- go.
接下来要进入50号标志的维修轨道
We're heading to a rip track just past milepost 5- 0.
我需要知道你们列车的位置
We need to know the location of your yard's train.
它刚经过47号哩程标
It just passed milepost 47.
这下糟了
Holy shit.
他们想让它进入侧线但失败了 导引车因此脱轨翻覆
They tried to side it. but it jumped the switch and derailed the lash- up.
导引车? 谁是驾驶?
Lash- up? Who was driving?
拥有26年资历的机师杰德史都华
The engineer, a 26- year rail company veteran,
在基丁峰丧生
was killed earlier today in Keating Summit, central Pennsylvania.
杰德史都华
Judd Stewart.
史都华?
Stewart?
你说史都华?
You said Stewart?
杰德史都华 来自布鲁斯特的机师
Judd Stewart. an engineer from Brewster.
你认识他?
You know him?
你车头有多少马力?
What's your power on the point?
5000匹 它没有很强
5.000 horses. She's not a hotshot.
但还算有力
but she's still got some life left in her. over.
让它好好表现 告诉盖文有两个公司的人在主线上
Give her all you got. Tell Galvin we got two guys out on the mainline
准备跟我们的车对撞
about to play chicken with our train.
- 我们试过但失败了 - 怎么了?
- We tried to stop it. We blew it. - What?
火车得被摧毁
That train's got to go down.
问题是要怎么减低损伤
The only question is how to minimize the damage.
大家安静!
Quiet!
我们刚得知有另一辆列车在轨道上
We just learned there is yet another train on this track,
正朝着失控列车过去
headed directly at the runaway.
这是什么?
What the hell is this?
我们竟然要看电视才知道?
We gotta learn about it on damn TV?
妮琪 听着 别挂电话
Nicole. Listen. don't hang up. Don't hang up.
爸 我正在忙
Dad. I'm busy. Okay?
我了解
Okay, I understand.
我只是想告诉你我爱你们而已
Dad? I just wanted to tell you I love you.
别肉麻了 爸 发生什么事?
that's all. Okay. fine! Dad. what's wrong?
没事 我只是...
Nothing. nothing. I just...
爸 怎么了?
Dad. what's wrong?
告诉你妹妹我爱你们 好吗? 我得挂了
Just tell your sister I love you both. okay? I got to go.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
1206 你们还好吗?
1 206. how are you holding up?
距离维修轨道还有半哩
About a half a mile from that rip track. Over.
你们随时会看到777的车头
Chances are you're going to see 777's nose any minute now.
了解
Affirmative.
为什么要刹车?
Why are you braking?
相信我 速度太快我们就会脱轨
Trust me. If we head in this hot. we'll tear right off the track.
天啊
Oh. Jesus.
减速到40 小心碰撞
Get her down to 40 and brace yourself.
得想办法让十节车厢进入侧线
You need to get at least 1 0 cars into the siding.
太好了!
Yes!
法兰克 切换到六频道
Frank, go to 6. Frank, go to 6.
我在六频道 请说
Yeah. I'm at 6. Go.
他们要疏散阿克罗镇
They're evacuating Arklow.
他们要让列车脱轨
They're going to derail the train.
他们要用什么?
What are they using?
标准脱轨设备
Standard DRE.
移动式脱轨装置
Yeah. a portable derailer.
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
那辆车最后一个连接器看来是开的
I got a look at that train's last coupler knuckle. it was open.
我们现在出发 我们回到主线上
We take off right now. we get back on the main.
就能倒退追上列车
we can chase it down in reverse.
追? 等等
Chase? Whoa. wait a minute.
要阻止这种动力只能抓住列车尾
The only way to stop that kind of power. grab it by the tail.
往反方向拉
boom. gun it in the opposite direction.
我们不能冒险 万一列车脱轨
We can't just chase it down. If it goes down.
我们就惨了
we're gonna be a wreck on a wreck.
不重要 列车应该不太可能会脱轨
Doesn't matter. There's a good chance the derailer won't work.
那东西都已经叫脱轨器了!
It's called a derailer. for Christ's sake!
它的作用就是让火车脱轨
That's what they do! A train that size
这么巨大又爆速的列车 只要被它撞到就会人问蒸发
going that fast. it will vaporize anything that gets in its way.
狗屁 没把握他们就不会用
Bullshit! They wouldn't use it if...
他们错了 好吗? 他们错了
They're wrong. all right? They're wrong.
你到底来不来?
Are you in or are you out?
你想找死就自己去
You want to get yourself killed. you do it alone.
问问你老婆看她怎么想
You know what? Ask your wife what she thinks.
等一下!
Wait!
如果脱轨器没作用
If you're right and that derailer fails.
列车开到斯坦顿的机率有多大?
what are the odds it makes it to Stanton?
你刚刚有看到 你说呢?
You saw the train. What do you think?
1206 我是康妮胡波 你们在吗?
1 206. this is Connie Hooper. Are you there?
1206 请说
1 206. Over.
只是想问问你们的状况
Just wanted to see how you boys are doing.
现在时速大约60哩 康妮
We're doing about 60 mile an hour. Connie.
什么? 法兰克 我不懂
Sorry? Frank. I don't understand.
我们要去追你的列车
We're going after your train.
1206 我不懂你意思
1206, I'm not hearing you.
车尾的连接器是开的
The rear knuckle was left open.
如果我们追得上 就可以接到我们的车头
so if we can catch up. we can tie it on to our locomotive.
让777慢下来
try and slow down 777.
法兰克 你不能这样
Frank. you can't.
我已经做了
We already are.
携带式脱轨器没有用的
Portable derailer's not gonna cut it. Connie.
谁说要用脱轨器了?
Who said anything about a derailer?
调度场说要撤离阿克罗镇的居民
Dispatch. they said that they're evacuating Arklow.
猜都猜的到
Two plus two is four.
- 奈德打来 他说还在追踪... - 不
- It's Ned. He said he's still following... - No. No. No.
告诉他我会回电 马上打给盖文
Tell him I'll call him back. Get me Galvin. now.
车上有三万加仑的有毒物质
Frank. that train's carrying 30.000 gallons of toxic chemicals.
刚刚本来有机会的 但火车正开往人口稠密的地区
They had a window before. but that train's going into populated areas.
现在不能让它脱轨了
There's no way they'd derail it now.
你确定吗?
Are you sure about that?
让我先打电话确定
Look. Iet me make some calls.
请打电话确定
Make some calls. Please.
你觉得他们能赶上吗?
What do you think? Do you think they can catch up?
有可能 但就算他们赶上了
Possibly. But even if they do.
他们要在一般速度快十倍下连结 还是反方向
we're talking about coupling at 1 0 times the normal speed. in reverse.
我以为你比较想让车脱轨
I thought you were in favor of derailment.
那时列车还在偏僻的地方
Yeah. when they were in the middle of nowhere. not now.
但现在列车要开到城镇里了!
It's just town after town out there!
盖文说要再打给你
Mr. Galvin says he'd have to call you back.
我是康妮胡波 找盖文先生
This is Connie Hooper for Mr. Galvin.
他在开会
Mr. Galvin is in a meeting.
那么你来告诉我 公司决定要让777脱轨吗?
Then maybe you can tell me. Is the company planning on derailing 777?
之前我听说的是盖文死命反对
Last I heard. Galvin was dead set against it.
抱歉 恕我爱莫能助
I'm sorry, I'd really like to help you, Ms. Hooper.
我没有办法代表公司回应
But I'm not at liberty to give you that information.
不 你当然无权这么做
No. of course you're not at liberty to.
法兰克说对了
Frank's right.
这种单引擎可以开多快?
What's the fastest you've taken a single engine like this?
- 没挂车厢吗? - 没错
- Unattached? - Yeah.
50到55哩
Fifty. 55.
那是往前进的话
Of course. I was going forward.
1206 听到了吗?
1206, you there?
1206回话 完毕
This is 1 206. over.
法兰克 你说对了
Frank, you're right.
他们是要想让车脱轨
About the derailment.
他们预计在阿克罗镇外行动
They're planning an attempt outside of Arklow.
告诉他们不会成功
Tell them idiots it ain't gonna work.
携带式脱轨器没有用
That portable derailer. it's worthless.
她已经跟我们说过了
She already told us.
他是公司的营运副总我奥斯卡盖文
Frank. this is Oscar Galvin. VP of Operations.
他要求进入通话 把麦克风打开
patched in at his request. open mike.
对 我们要让777脱轨 法兰克 这是既成的决定
Yeah. we're derailing 777. Frank. It's a done decision.
不管你喜不喜欢 这是我们目前最好的选择
Like it or not, it's our best option at this stage.
在阿克罗镇脱轨的损害比较小
There'll be less collateral damage in Arklow.
我们已经撤离那里的居民
It's already being evacuated.
我们不能让777开到斯坦顿
and we can't let 777 make it to Stanton.
我无意冒犯
Look. Mr. Galvin. with all due respect.
我在铁路已经工作了28年
I've been railroading 28 years.
我们很有机会让列车停下来
I'm telling you. we got a real chance to stop this thing.
我们已经试过了
No. we already tried.
那是从前面 我们要从后面拉住它
That was from the front. We're long hood lead back.
情况不同 我们比较能控制列车
It's a different situation. We got more control now.
如果我取消脱轨行动 而你失败了怎么办?
What if I cancel the derailer and you fail. Frank?
列车会以时速70哩
That train will be doing 70 miles an hour
冲向斯坦顿
into that elevated S- curve in Stanton.
损失会比现在多出百倍
The damage will be 1 00 times worse.
但我要说携带式脱轨器没有用
Right. I'm just telling you. the portable derailer is worthless.
目前的车厢太多也开得太快
You got too much train traveling entirely too fast.
也许可以让1206支援
Maybe 1 206 should just stay on it as a backup.
我不会让更多人员或财产受到危害
Look. I am not jeopardizing more personnel and more property
只因为有某个机师想逞英雄
just because some engineer wants to play hero.
讨论到此结束!
End of discussion!
那辆列车是我们的财产 由我们做决定!
That train is our property. It's our decision!
你现在就停车 不然我就开除你!
Now you stop your pursuit or I will fire you!
你已经开除我了
Fire. You already did.
已经怎么样?
Already did what?
你已经开除我了
You've already fired me.
我已经收到90天的通知信了 就在72天前
I received my 90- day notice in the mail 72 days ago.
强制提早退休 红利减半
Forced early retirement. half benefits.
所以你只剩3个礼拜 却还是要为我们冒生命危险?
So you're going to risk your life for us with three weeks left.
不是为了你们
Not for you.
我这么做不是为了你们
I'm not doing it for you.
法兰克 把无线电给我
Frank. Let me see that thing.
盖文先生 我是列车长威尔考森
Mr. Galvin. this is Will Colson. your conductor.
我要告诉你 我们要追到列车
I'm letting you know. we're going to run this bitch down.
你没听到我刚刚说的吗 考森? 我会开除你!
Maybe you didn't hear what I just said. Colson. I will fire you!
真可惜 我才开始喜欢上这份工作呢
Well. that's too bad. I was just starting to like this job.
该死 你给我听着 你这混蛋 你会被开除的!
God damn it, you listen to me! You son of a bitch! You will be fired!
讯号不清楚...
You're breaking up. Sorry. you're...
- 别胡说了... - 长官 我想他们已经收不到了
- This garbage is... - Sir. I think they're gone.
现在他们是你的问题了 胡波
This is your headache now. Hooper.
你得让他们离开主线 不然你自己工作也不保!
Now you get them off the main or consider yourself shit- canned. too!
我喜欢他们
I like them.
让我看进入阿克罗镇的路线图
Bring up Beech Siding to Arklow.
各位可以看到大家正在紧急撤离
Take a look behind me, you can see emergency evacuation measures
这里是铁轨旁的小镇阿克罗
are currently in effect right here in the tiny town of Arklow.
导引车失败
The lash- up was a no- go.
1206呼叫富勒调度场 康妮 你在吗?
1 206 to Fuller Yard. Connie. are you there? Over.
法兰克 我为盖文的态度道歉
Frank. I'm real sorry about Galvin.
没关系 他挂断了吗?
That's okay. Listen. Iisten. Is he off?
对 他挂电话了
Yeah. he's gone.
听着
Okay. Iisten up.
我要你帮我们一个忙
I'm going to need you to do us a favor.
我需要你随时告诉我们777的速度与位置
I need you to keep us posted on the speed and location of 777.
位置和速度 完毕
Location and speed. Over.
康妮?
Connie?
777在阿克罗镇外9哩
Frank. 777's 9 miles out of Arklow.
你得快点赶上它
You got some catching up to do.
阿克罗镇外9哩
9 miles out of Arklow.
你说你老婆叫什么名字?
What did you say your wife's first name was?
达儿希
Darcy.
你说来话长的故事是什么?
So. what was the long story you didn't want to make long?
2周前有天我回家
I come home from work two weeks ago
看到她在传简讯
and she's texting on the phone.
我问她传给谁 她说不重要
I ask her who with. she says. "Nobody."
我要她给我看电话 她不要
I say. "Let me see the phone." She says no.
这件事发生了五、六次...
This goes on five or six times.
我没听懂 她传简讯...?
Wait. you're losing me. She's texting...
有个家伙是我们以前同学
There's this guy we both went to school with.
他现在是州警
He's a cop. he's a PA state trooper.
他喜欢达儿希很久了
He's always had a thing for Darcy. Going way back.
1206 你们在哪里?
1206, where are you?
1206回覆 康妮 我们刚刚通过57号哩程标
1 206 here. Connie. We're just passing milepost 5- 7.
你们大约还落后1.5哩
You're about a mile and a half behind.
777离阿克罗镇还有多远?
How far out of Arklow is 777?
7.5哩 还在加速 你们动作要快
Seven and a half miles. It picked up speed. You better step on it.
我们全速前进中
I'm stepping on it. in it. around it and through it. Connie.
谢谢 完毕
Thank you. Over.
她不断传简讯 我一直问她 她一直说没事
She's texting on the phone. I keep on asking for it. she keeps on saying no.
然后她走开 我抓住她...
She starts to walk away and I grab for it.
- 你打她? - 我没有
- You hit her? - No. no. no.
我吓吓她 但我没有打她
I mean. I scared her. but I didn't hit her.
总之我开车到那家伙的家
Anyway. I drive to this guy's house
说我们得谈谈
and tell him we need to talk. Iet's take a ride.
他上了我的车后说
He jumps in my truck and starts in with.
"你误会了 他们只是朋友
"You got it all wrong. We're just friends."
然后他停下来 他看到...
Then he stops once he sees
我的车上有枪!
the gun I got sitting on the dash. Oh!
我看着他 跟他说 "这是我老婆 你去找别人当朋友吧
I look him in the eye and say. "She's my wife. You find a new friend."
你对警察掏枪?
You pulled a gun on a cop?
法兰克?
Frank?
777刚通过61号哩程标
Frank. 777 just passed milepost 61.
谢谢你 康妮
Thank you. Connie.
- 你想要听更劲爆的吗? - 我想
- You want to hear the kicker? - Yes. I do.
结果她传简讯的对象不是他 是我的小姨子
It wasn't even him that was texting her. It was my sister- in- law.
总之等我到家 他的同事等候多时
Anyway. by the time I got home. his buddy's waiting for me.
等着拿禁制令给我
just waiting to serve me with this restraining order.
达儿希连看都不看我
Darcy wouldn't even look at me.
我跟我哥住
So I'm living with my brother.
今天有一场听证会 法官把禁制令又延长了30天
There was a hearing today. The judge ordered a 30- day extension.
本来一切还好好的
It's like one day everything's going okay.
突然有一天一切都敌了
and the next. it's all falling apart faster
再也无法复原
than you can put it back together.
但总是不嫌太迟的
Yeah. Never too late. though.
福斯电视台
头条新闱
这辆39节车厢的失控列车
The plan to derail this 39- car runaway train
就要进行脱轨计划了
is just minutes away now.
现场非常骚动
There's a tremendous amount of activity going on.
这辆火车到底会不会停止呢?
Will this train be able to be stopped?
1206刚刚通过62号哩程标
1 206. Connie. We're just passing milepost 6- 2.
62号哩程标
Milepost 6- 2, over.
还差一哩多
Still a mile gap. maybe more.
我们不够快
We're not gaining on her. Frank.
等等
Hold on.
这就像去打靶!
It's just like the shooting range!
来了 准备行动!
All right. here we go! Come on! Let's go! This is it! It's game time!
阿克罗镇北方2.1哩
注意瞄准红色的安全闸!
Remember. we're aiming for the red circular button!
射击!
Now!
停火 你们打到油箱盖了 见鬼!
Hold your fire! You're shooting the fuel cap. God damn it!
停火!
Hold your fire!
我们本来要对安全闸开火
We were aiming to disable it by firing shotgun rounds
让列车停下来 我们开了几枪...
at a fuel stop safety switch, and so some shots were fired.
安全闸是很小的目标
That safety switch is a mighty small target.
位置就在油箱旁边
And it's right next to a fuel tank.
我们没办法在阿克罗镇前赶上它
We're not gonna catch it before Arklow.
法兰克 你们越来越近了 速度放慢
Frank. you're closing the gap. You should cut your speed.
留一点刹车的距离
Allow yourself some stopping distance. Just in case.
没办法 我们现在减速就追不上
No can do. Connie. If we slow down now. we'll never catch it.
在斯坦顿之前追不上
Not before Stanton. Over.
你来决定
It's your call.
我们得到消息 有二位铁路员工
However, we have now also learned that two railroad employees
正搭来一辆火车头追赶777
are now in pursuit of train 777 in a single locomotive.
目前还不知道他们追赶火车的计划...
It is unclear what their plan is...
康妮胡波打来了
Connie Hooper for you.
我不是要你让1206离开主线了?
Did I or did I not tell you to get 1 206 off the main?
我态度很好地跟他们说了啊
I asked them nicely.
你百分之百确定脱轨器没用?
You're 1 00% sure that derailer won't work?
百分之百不确定
Yes. 1 00%? No.
会成功还是不成功?
Which one is it?
- 机率一半一半 - 真好笑
- 50- 50. - Pretty funny.
如果它真的有用呢?
And if it does?
如果有用 我们就惨了
If it does. then we're a wreck on a wreck.
这位是联邦铁路局的金恩
I'm here with FRA official Gene Devereaux.
火车正在逼近 你们要怎么做?
This train is getting close. How is this going to work?
基本上它的作用就像斜坡
Basically, it works like a ramp.
列车开过来
The train comes along,
这个东西就会往上 把列车拉离轨道
this piece here will lift the flange and pull it outside the rail.
这样列车就会往右翻倒
That will cause the train to flip over on its right- hand side.
让列车措手不及
Son of a bitch won 't even know what hit it.
列车距离这里4分钟了!
Train's about four minutes out!
快发车!
Guys. come on. Get it started!
大家动作快!
Guys. come on!
阿克罗镇北方0.5哩
- 失败了! - 怎么回事?
- It has not succeeded! - What?
那是怎么一回事?
What in the hell was that?
那辆列车有1千万吨 盖文先生!
That was 1 0 million pounds of train. Mr. Galvin!
而这是我拯救你的声音!
And this is the sound of me saving your ass!
法兰克 听到了吗?
Frank. do you copy?
法兰克?
Frank?
1206号车回覆
This is 1 206. Over.
你说对了 火车连颠都没颠
You were right. It barely bumped.
我的老天
Jesus Christ.
我们在现场为各位报导
We're bringing you live coverage right now
这可能会酿成宾州史上
on what could very well result in one of the worst disasters
最大灾难
in the history of the state of Pennsylvania.
细节还要再调查
Now, the particulars are still being examined,
但当局更关注...
but authorities are far more focused
777若在斯坦顿脱轨
on the potential destruction that would result if train 777
可能的危害
were to derail in Stanton.
你说自己结过一次婚是什么意思?
What'd you mean about being married once?
我老婆艾丽丝死于癌症
Alice. my wife. she died of cancer.
- 4年前的事 - 我很遗憾
- Four years ago. - I'm sorry.
我也是
Me. too.
每天晚上我回家都会和她分享工作
Every night. I'd come home. tell her about my day.
我去了哪里 做了什么
where I'd been. what I hauled.
还有谁让我觉得讨厌
who annoyed me.
我晚上应该会跟她说到你
Guess I would have made the evening report. huh?
你绝对会说
Yes. you would have made it. definitely.
你应该打电话给你老婆
You should call your wife.
她今天休假 大概还在睡觉
I would. but it's her day off. She's probably sleeping.
别找藉口 吵醒她吧
Don't make excuses. Wake her up.
我打了二礼拜的电话了
Been calling for the past two weeks.
她一通都没有回
She still hasn't called me back.
她不会回的 你要自己打给她
She won't. You got to call her.
你搞不懂吗? 你太快放弃了
Don't you know how that works? You quit too easy.
宾州斯坦顿
达儿希!
Darcy!
我一直在打电话给你
I have been calling and calling.
怎么了?
What is wrong?
如我们稍早报导的
As we told you earlier today, those emergency evacuations
今早这里有紧急撤离行动 以求居民安全
began early this morning as they try to move people out of harm's way.
这是管制区域 现场的消防员...
You get a sense of the perimeter here. You see the firefighters...
是我 我们正要出发
Hey. it's me. Yeah. we're on our way.
我知道 我正在看
Yeah. I know. I'm watching it.
宾州阿克罗
有二名铁路员工正驾驶一辆火车头
Two railroad employees are presently in pursuit of train 777
追赶777号列车
in a single locomotive.
似乎没人清楚如果他们赶上列车
No one seems exactly clear on what their plans are
打算怎么做
should they catch up to that train.
是爸爸
It's Dad.
我们刚刚得知法兰克巴恩
We have just learned that railroad employee Frank Barnes,
28年年资 负责列车驾驶...
a 28- year veteran of the freight company responsible for the runaway,
还有列车长威尔考森都在车上
and Will Colson, a conductor, are now onboard another locomotive.
我们要过去了
We're on our way.
他们试图追赶...
A single locomotive trying to catch up
- 失控列车 - 她需要穿衣服
- to the runaway train. - She's gotta get dressed.
- 为了成功 他们... - 我看到了
- And get this. They were traveling... - I can tell.
她马上过去
She'll be ready in a minute.
... 以时速70哩反向前进
... at speeds of up to 70 miles an hour in reverse.
777号列车现在距离...只有短短几英里路程
777 is now just miles away from the significantly...
达儿希 快去穿衣服
Come on. Darcy. Iet's go. Come on. get dressed.
...人口更加密集的斯坦顿
...more populated town of Stanton.
快走!
Let's go. boys!
距离斯坦顿11哩
你们已经接近了
Okay. you're getting close.
相差1哩 777离斯坦顿有10哩
The gap's at a mile and 777 is 1 0 miles to Stanton.
听着 法兰克 这里有位联邦铁路局来的人
Now. Iisten. Frank. I got a guy here named Werner from the FRA.
我不想质疑你的判断 但...
Now. I'm inclined to defer to your judgment here. but he...
让他说话 我们有越多协助越好
All right. Put him on. We could use all the help we can get.
压住这个键说话
Just press this and hold to talk.
你们一接上777就要让它减速
It's about slowing 777 once you've tied on.
我知道传统上...
I know conventional wisdom says
会要你往反方向拉它就好
to just gun it in the opposite direction.
但如果你用动力刹车
But you'll have a better shot
跟前进的动力轮替比较会成功
alternating full throttle with dynamic braking.
但我们不能失去反推力
Yeah. but we can't afford to lose counterthrust.
失去的反推力
What you'll lose in counterthrust
会被牵引力抵销
you'll compensate for in tractive force.
你确定吗?
Are you sure about that?
这是我快速推算后的直觉
Well. it's more of a hunch based on some quick calculations.
是直觉啊
It's a hunch.
我时速70哩 他居然只靠直觉
I'm 70 miles an hour and he's giving us a hunch.
谢谢 请让康妮听电话
Okay. Thank you. Put Connie back on. please.
是我 法兰克
It's me, Frank.
康妮 这家伙懂吗?
Yeah. Connie. does this guy know what he's talking about?
在理想的情况下
In a perfect world.
我会说他懂
yes. I'd say yes.
理想的情况...好吧
In a perfect world. okay.
在宾州郊区失控的列车后续报导
We have more now on that runaway freight train in rural Pennsylvania.
他们提出一个让列车停止的计划
They've devised an ambitious plan to bring it to a stop.
让另外一个车头从后面接近列车
A single locomotive moves in from behind,
赶上、连结 然后刹车 好让它减速
catches up, hooks up and then brakes in an effort to slow it down.
通过76号哩程标 康妮
Passing milepost 7 - 6. Connie. Over.
只差半哩了
You're only a half mile away.
半哩 好
Half a mile. Out.
法兰克 既然是反向 你要怎么判断后方相差的距离?
Frank. running in reverse. how are you gonna gauge our gap distance?
我可以到外面给你打手势
I could go out there. I could signal you by hand.
在时速70哩的时候?
At 70 mile an hour?
不管 这样有用吗?
I'm asking. Would it help?
好 用对讲机跟手势
All right. Radio and hand signals.
我们一起合作 你要小心
We'll combinate. And be careful.
我会
I will.
还有 把背心脱掉
And take that vest off. too.
- 为什么? - 叫你脱 你就脱
- Why? - Just take it off.
我不想往后
I don't want to look out this window
看到你穿着黄背心 我会吓坏
and see you in that yellow vest. It'll freak me out.
接电话啊 威尔
Come on. Will.
快接电话
Pick up. Come on.
我是威尔 请留言...
This is Will. Leave me a message.
该死!
Damn!
距离十节车厢!
Ten cars. Frank!
我知道了
Affirmative. Over.
接近了!
All right. here she comes!
相差约三节车厢?
Three cars?
三节车厢 收到
Three cars steady. Copy.
稳住!
All right. Steady, steady!
距离两节车厢?
Two cars?
两节车厢 收到
Yeah. two cars. Copy.
稳住
Steady. Over.
再来 再来!
Keep it coming. keep it coming!
再来!
Keep it coming!
稳住 稳住!
Steady. steady!
威尔考森试着连结1206
Will Colson is trying to hook up 1206
- 和777 - 我的天哪
- with 777. - Oh. my God.
出了严重的差错
Something has gone terribly wrong.
威尔 怎么回事?
Will. what was that?
谷粒被吹飞了!
The grain car blew a seal!
我们连结上了吗?
Are we tied off?
怎么回事?
Will, what's going on?
现在看到的是救援行动的现场画面
Right now we are looking at live pictures of this rescue operation.
我们连结上了吗?
Are we tied off?
没有 连结器关上了!
No. Frank. it didn't work. Our knuckle closed!
威尔 跟我比手势 用手势!
Will. use hand signals! Hand signals!
连结上了吗?
We tied on?
好了 好了!
We're good! We're good!
你说什么?
What?
该死
Oh. shit.
法兰克 连结器没有落锁!
Frank. the pin didn't fall!
再说一次 什么?
Say again. The what?
我们接上了没?
Will. are we tied on?
不行 连结器没有落锁
It's not gonna work. The pin didn't fall.
什么?
What?
连结器有问题 没有锁上!
The pin didn't fall! It's not locking!
好 听着
All right. well. Iook.
下去看看可以怎么办 你要小心!
Try and get down there. see what you can do. Be careful!
你要小心
Be careful.
威尔!
Will!
列车没有减速 反倒加速了
It's not slowing down. It's gaining speed right now.
他到下面去连接...
He's reaching down, trying to couple...
威尔 你收得到吗?
Will. can you read me?
他不见了!
He's gone!
威尔考森滑下去了 我们看不见他
Will Colson is down. We do not see him.
43号直升机能将镜头拉近吗?
Chopper 43, can you zoom in?
- 我们看不到列车长威尔考森 - 加油 宝贝
- We do not see the conductor, Colson. - Come on. baby.
威尔 你收得到吗? 威尔!
Will. can you read me? Will!
43号直升机 拉近镜头 看到他了 威尔考森
Chopper 43, zoom in. There he is. Will Colson.
他挣扎着把自己拉上来
As he struggles to pull himself up,
看来威尔考森有麻烦了
Iooks like Will Colson is in trouble.
二辆车连接了
The train is coupled.
我听说二辆车已经接好了
I'm now being told that the connection has been made.
看起来列车连接上了
It looks as though this train is now attached.
1206已经成功接上777
1 206 has been successfully attached to 777.
但威尔考森似乎受伤了
But it looks like Will Colson is injured.
你还好吗?
You all right?
我很好
I'm great.
不要碰触靴子
Hey. hey. don't touch that! Don't touch that boot!
用这个缠住就好!
Here. just wrap it up with this.
整个都缠好 紧紧缠住
Wrap it real tight. all around.
你还可以吗?
You okay?
没事 没事
I'm all right. I'm all right.
巴恩和考森赶上了这辆失控列车
Barnes and Colson have caught up to the runaway train.
达儿希 走吧
Darcy. come on. Come on.
但火车依旧以75哩的时速
But the train continues to speed in excess of 75 miles an hour,
往斯坦顿前进
heading to Stanton.
康妮 现在距离多远?
Connie. how far we got?
距离斯坦顿多远?
How far to Stanton? Over.
还有4哩 你们做得很棒
4 miles. You guys are doing great.
但时间紧迫
You're cutting it close. though.
威尔怎么样?
How's Will?
他很惨 完毕
He's... He's different. Over.
准备好拔河了吗?
Ready for a little tug- of- war?
来吧
Let's do it.
我们要试着跟列车的速度一致
Match our speed with theirs.
- 我们会扯断连结 - 不会的
- Frank. we're gonna snap right off. - No. we're not. we're not.
只是会拉扯而已 没事的
We're just stretching. that's all. We're just stretching.
斯坦顿
Here in Stanton,
持续撤离全镇居民
the evacuation procedures continue for the entire town.
主线轨道会在这里升高进入弯道
This is the town where that mainline train track turns into an elevated curve.
据说这辆高速的...
They say there is virtually no chance
失控列车几乎不可能
this speeding, out- of- control train
通过这个弯道
will make it through that curve.
我们应该要减速
We should be slowing down.
但是没有
Which we're not.
该死
Shoot.
改用动力刹车 跟全速前进轮替
Go to the dynamic. Alternate full throttle.
那些刹车快被操斓了
Christ! Those cab brakes are getting a workout.
...因为载运有害物质...
...because of the highly toxic nature of the cargo.
法兰克 加油
Come on. Frank.
减速吧 宝贝
Come on. baby.
我们速度多少?
What's our speed?
低于50哩了
We're under 50.
康妮 目前距离多远?
Connie. how far away?
3哩 我已经安排人手待命
3 miles. FRA's got men on the ground ready to hop onboard
你们一减速到20他们就会跳上车
as soon as you guys get it under 20.
叫他们准备跳吧
All right. Tell them. be ready to hop. Over.
该死!
Shoot!
- 怎么回事? - 速度加快了
- What is it? - We're gaining speed.
列车太重 我们被拖着走了
Consist is too heavy. We're being dragged.
康妮!
Connie!
我在这里 法兰克
I'm here. Frank.
我们的速度太快了
We're gonna be coming in too hot.
通知联邦铁路局的人
Let them know.
弯道的速限是15哩
The limit on that curve is 1 5.
快太多就过不去 顶多20到25还可以?
I don't know if you can take it much faster. maybe 20. 25. max?
我没有选择 告诉他们我们的速度会很快
We may not have a choice. Just tell them it's gonna be real hot.
车厢的刹车可不可以用?
What about the braking on the freight cars?
很好
Good. good.
我来
All right. I'm on it.
坐下 我去 你坐好
Just sit down. No. no. I've got it. Sit tight.
我到外面去 你过来吧
I'll go out. Sit down. No. in fact. come here.
你坐在这边 我到外面去
You sit here. I'll go out.
维持在4
Just keep it at four.
可以吗?
You all right? Take it easy. Yeah.
握住刹车把手推到4
Hold that dynamic at a four. Four.
必要时跟前进动力搭配
Integrate it with the throttle if you have to.
维持在4 跟前进动力搭配
Hold it at a four. integrate the throttle.
尽量操刹车块 不重要
Burn the block out. it doesn't matter.
别突然感伤起来
Hey. don't get sentimental on me.
你让我感觉我快死了 你握好就对
Makes me think I'm gonna die. Just hold that four.
加油 法兰克
Come on. Frank.
铁路公司不予置评
AWVR officials have no comment.
巴恩要动手 将777最后一节车厢煞住
Barnes is attempting to manually brake the last car of 777.
他在列车项上迸走...
He's actually running on top of the grain cars and jumping...
法兰克 加油
Way to go. Frank. Let's go. Frank.
看来777的确减速了
Looks like 777 is slowing down.
我们明白 这么做
We understand this is some sort of
是为了让列车减速
an attempt to try and stop the train.
好样的 加油! 你可以的!
Yes! Come on. come on! You can do it!
你们现在速度多少?
Will. how fast you going?
34哩
34.
我们在减速了 33哩
All right. we're dropping. 33.
铁路公司发言人确认...
The railroad spokesman just confirmed he is...
- 这样管用吗? - ...巴恩现在动手
- Think it'll work? - ...attempting to slow 777
把各车厢刹车开启
by manually braking each car.
理论上可行
Theoretically.
只要车头的独立刹车没问题
Provided that locomotive's independent brake holds out.
继续在斯坦顿现场报导
We continue to bring you live coverage of this breaking news event
头条新闱
from the town of Stanton.
紧急小组划出管制区...
Emergency management officials have created this perimeter.
这是警察 请撤离屋项
This is the police. Get off the roof.
为了你们的安全 请马上离开
You are being asked to evacuate for your own safety.
该死!
Shit!
法兰克!
Frank!
我听到了!
Yeah. I hear you. I hear you!
我们的刹车坏了!
We just lost our brakes!
看来刹车爆了
Looks like the brakes have blown.
见鬼!
Shit!
法兰克 法兰克 你没事吧?
Frank! Frank. you all right?
我没事 威尔 怎么回事?
I'm here. Will. What happened?
我们又加速了
We're picking up speed again.
你能不能设法让它减速? 我们快到弯道了
Can you still slow it down? We're almost at the curve.
法兰克 引擎已经过热了
Frank. our engine block's overheated.
我认为手动刹车
I don't think those hand brakes are gonna
也没办法减速
have the muscle to stop this thing.
速度实在太快
We're creeping up fast.
你用独立刹车吧
All right. well. just hang on to the independent.
我会告诉你时间点
I'll tell you when.
火车进入第二级的高架铁轨 这里的时速限制是15哩
Elevated and strictly Class 2, speed restricted to 1 5 miles per hour.
正下方的三栋建筑
Impact with at least three of these buildings
会无法幸免
directly below will be unavoidable,
这里的燃料槽也一样
as will contact with all the fuel storage tanks situated here.
威尔? 威尔
Will? Will.
我们没事
We're all right. we're all right.
但速度又加快了
but we're picking up speed again.
威尔!
Will!
我们要进入弯道了 准备了!
We're coming into the curve! Get ready!
威尔 拉独立刹车杆!
Will! Hit that independent!
用力拉刹车杆!
Hit that independent as hard as you can!
我们会脱轨
Frank. we're gonna rip right off.
我们没有选择
Got no choice.
威尔 撑住!
Will! Hang on!
拉! 再拉一次!
Hit it! Hit it again!
就是现在!
Now!
法兰克 你没事吧?
Frank. you all right?
我们成功了 通过弯道了 他们成功通过弯道了
We made it! We made it! We're through the curve.
777成功了 已经通过弯道
777 made it. It made it through the Stanton curve.
777已经通过弯道
777 is through the Stanton curve,
但问题还没有结束
but by no means out of trouble.
777正在加速 失去控制 必须要让它脱轨才行
777 is gaining speed. It is out of control and has to derail.
法兰克和威尔
Frank Barnes and Will Colson will be
会成为东北区史上
the victims of the biggest rail disaster
最严重铁路意外的受害者
in the history of the northeast.
看来法兰克巴忍拼了
It looks like Frank Barnes is making an all- out effort.
太好了
Good job.
了不起 他要前往777的车头
This is a remarkable effort now to get to the front of 777.
法兰克!
Frank!
我们速度到60了 很快就会到80哩!
We're at... We're at 60. and we're going to hit 80 in no time!
他过不去
He's not gonna make it.
看来车厢间的距离让他止步了
Looks like the gap between cars has stopped him.
继续啊!
You can do it!
列车持续以75哩的时速前进
But the train continues to speed in excess of 75 miles an hour.
法兰克 法兰克!
Frank! Frank!
有问题了
Will. we got a problem here.
我做不到
I don't think I can make it.
天啊
Oh. God.
是奈德!
There's Ned!
不可思议 不可思议
Unbelievable. Unbelievable.
奈德 我是康妮
Hello. Ned. it's Connie.
我现在有点忙 康妮 我再打给你
I'm kind of busy right now. Connie. I'll call you back.
嘿!
Hey!
跳啊!
Come on!
跳到卡车后车厢!
Hop in the back of the truck!
康妮 那辆卡车是来帮我们的吗?
Connie? Connie. is that truck for us?
是 威尔 你做得到
Yes. it is. Will. You can do this.
你可以的!
Will, you can do this!
加油!
Come on!
...停止列车 在主线...
看来他们想要获得
Looks like he's trying to synchronize
与火车同步的速度
the speed of the pickup with the train.
快跳 不要犹豫 跳到后面!
Do it. you pussy! Jump in the back!
好样的!
Yes! Yes!
Yeah!
好样的!
真是千钧一发
And look at what's happening now.
红色卡车要把他载到车头
The red pickup racing to the front of 777.
加油
Come on. Will.
法兰克!
Frank!
快去 快往前!
Go! Just go! Go. go. go!
快点 快去!
Go. go. go!
冲吧!
Go. go!
奈德快要没有路可以跑了
Ned Oldham is running out of parallel road.
加油 威尔
Come on. Will.
奈德 快开啊!
Drive. Ned!
他企图登上列车
He will attempt to board this train.
- 快点 - 该死
- Come on! - Shit!
见鬼 过头了!
God damn it! I overshot it!
加油啊
Come on.
快跳啊 快!
There it is. kid! Do it!
跳啊 快点 跳!
Come on. jump! Do it! Jump!
太好了!
Yes!
爸 加油!
Go. Dad!
好样的!
Yeah! Yeah!
Yeah! Yes! Yes! Yes!
天啊!
Oh. my God!
加油 威尔 加油!
Go! Go. Will!
威尔考森成功进入驾驶室
Will Colson successfully making it into the cab,
777受到控制了
now in control of 777.
43号直升机捕捉到这重大的一刻
Chopper 43 over this remarkable aftermath.
我们看到这二人的英雄事迹
We're talking about the heroic work of two men,
法兰克巴恩和威尔考森
Frank Barnes and Will Colson.
南宾州会永远感激他们
Southern Pennsylvania will always be indebted to them.
未接来电 达儿希
阿弥陀佛 我们做到了!
Judas Priest. we did it! We did it!
我知道把你弄上去就可以搞定 我是奈德奥德曼
I knew once we got you up there. we'd do it. Ned Oldham.
精准度最重要 小子 做得好
It's all about precision. Good job. kid.
- 你的脚受伤了 他割伤脚了 - 我觉得骨折了
- Your foot's hurt. He cut his foot! - I think it's broken.
他割伤脚了 找医护人员过来!
He cut his foot! Let's get some medics!
小子 过来
Get over here. kiddo.
- 奈德 - 你问!
- Ned! - You!
奈德 你当时很担心吗?
Ned. were you worried?
担心? 不 还好啊
Was I worried? Nah. Not really.
精准度最重要 天将大任于斯人...
It's all about precision. I wouldn't have undertaken such a task...
我刚刚接到公司的电话
Just got off the line with corporate.
是吗?
Oh. yeah?
说什么我们很感谢你啊
"Debt of gratitude." Blah. blah. blah.
我也是 其实感觉满爽的
Same here. Felt pretty good. actually.
是啦
Yeah. it did. actually.
...让事情完美的结束
...bringing it to a successful conclusion.
你发现这件事时有什么反应?
What was your first reaction when you realized what was happening?
我觉得自己有能力应变
I felt I was in my comfort zone.
他们对你的工作有什么说法?
What'd they say about your job?
我想的话可以留任
They said it's mine if I want to keep it.
不给你工作才蠢吧
They'd be stupid not to give it to you.
我也这么说
Yeah. That's what I told them.
他们最好给我一个更好的位置
Said they better think about giving me a better one. too.
- 那我呢? - 你怎样?
- How about me? - How about you?
- 结果成功了 - 奈德...
- As you can see, the result was a positive. - Ned...
你知道这一切是怎么发生的吗?
Do we have any better of an idea as to how this happened?
这个嘛...
Well, the thing that happened...
- 谢谢你的回答 奈德 - 我是奈德
- Thank you very much, Ned. - Everybody, this is Ned Oldham.
要回答这个问题...
To answer that last question...
抱歉 你能帮我一个忙吗?
Sorry. I wonder if you can help me.
康妮? 我无法决定
Connie? I can't decide
要先亲你们哪一个
which one of you I'm gonna kiss first.
当然是我啊
Me.
问题解决了
Problem solved.
来吧 康妮
Go get him. Connie.
过来吧
All right. Bring it on.
...感谢法兰克巴恩和威尔考森
...to Frank Barnes and Will Colson,
机师跟列车长的壮举...
the engineer and the conductor whose actions...
你女儿吗?
Your daughters?
43号直升机 完毕
Chopper 43, over and out.
When the song come on in the club
法兰克巴恩升官后开心退休
Turn it up Turn it up, turn it up Rewind!
The dance train is coming back again
他领到全额红利
Extravaganza, you should run and tell a friend
威尔考森与达儿希婚姻美满
第二个小孩即将出生
Kings and queens are posted at the bar
康妮胡波升迁担任营运副总我
Bucking down It's time to take it off
取代盖文的职位
Walk that walk Walk
Show me how you move it
雷恩史考特还健在
Can you walk that talk? Talk
Put some snap into it
杜伊目前从事速食业
Time to show it all
The spotlight is on you You better... Let's go!
Work, work, work, work
Work, work, work
You better shake that thing like a donkey
And go hard for it You better work
You better swing from a paw like a monkey
'Cause big girls get down on the floor
And make it jiggle, jiggle, jiggle You ain 't know
Ain 't no shame It's the name of the game
Now everybody down to the floor Here we go!
We got the rhythm of the beat
We got the rhythm of the hands
Let's get the rhythm of the feet
Jump in, jump out
Jump in, jump out Here we go
Work, work, work
Work, work, work You better work
仅此纪念荷莉诺顿及爱德利玛托